Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/harshasam (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

React.js

Node.js

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Languages

English

Sinhala

Certifications

Shaping up with Angular.js
Diploma in Computerised Accounting

Diploma in PC Hardware Engineering & Networking

Java Standalone Application Developer

Harsha Basnayake

Full Stack Software Engineer ➤ ReactJs | NodeJs | Javascript | Typescript | PHP | Laravel

Gampaha, Western Province, Sri Lanka

Summary

Skilled, accomplished software engineer with 7 years of experience in development, with key involvement in all stages of the software development life cycle. Demonstrated contributions to requirements analysis management, programming, testing, and deployment. Deep knowledge of Agile methodologies and industry IT standards. Talented problem solver with strong analytical abilities.

Experience

Surge Global
Senior Software Engineer (Full Stack)
July 2022 - Present (1 year 3 months)
Colombo, Western Province, Sri Lanka

Omobio (Pvt) Ltd.
Software Engineer
October 2020 - July 2022 (1 year 10 months)
Colombo District, Western, Sri Lanka

LI Studios (Pvt) Ltd 4 years 7 months

Senior Full Stack Developer
January 2018 - October 2020 (2 years 10 months)

Colombo District, Western, Sri Lanka

System Developer
April 2016 - January 2018 (1 year 10 months)
Colombo District, Western, Sri Lanka

Master Brand Web Developer April 2015 - April 2016 (1 year 1 month) Katunayaka

- → The role was responsible for designing, coding, and modifying websites, from layout to function according to a client's specifications.
- → Visited client places to install and train them in some of the distribution systems.
- → Fixed production issues.

Self-Employed

Freelance

January 2014 - April 2015 (1 year 4 months)

Kadawatha, Western Province, Sri Lanka

- → Designed and developed tailor-made web applications by gathering user requirements.
- → Developed Point-of-Sale desktop applications using JAVA SE with Hibernate and JasperReports.
- → Experienced and learned project success and failures when directly dealing with non-technical clients.

Education

London Metropolitan University

BEng (Hons), Software Engineering · (February 2021 - March 2022)

Pearson College London

HND, Computing and Systems Development · (2016 - 2019)

ESOFT Metro Campus

PC Hardware Engineering & Networking (2015 - 2016)

ESOFT Metro Campus

Computerized Accounting (2015 - 2015)

Java Institute for Advanced Technology

JSAD · (2012 - 2014)